<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Processes and Threds Overview</string>
    <string name="large_text">

        "Processes and threads overview\n"
        "This is an excerpt from Android Developer website\n\n"
        "Please fix the alignment as an exercise, using ctrl-enter at the end, I assume ...\n\n"

        "When an application component starts and the application does not have any other components running,
        the Android system starts a new Linux process for the application with a single thread of execution.
        By default, all components of the same application run in the same process and thread (called the main thread).
        If an application component starts and there already exists a process for that application
        (because another component from the application exists), then the component is started within that process
        and uses the same thread of execution. However, you can arrange for different components in your application
        to run in separate processes, and you can create additional threads for any process.\n\n"

        "Processes\n"
        "By default, all components of the same application run in the same process and most applications should not change this.
        However, if you find that you need to control which process a certain component belongs to, you can do so in the manifest file.\n\n"
        "Android might decide to shut down a process at some point, when memory is low and required by other processes
        that are more immediately serving the user.
        Application components running in the process that's killed are consequently destroyed.
        A process is started again for those components when there's again work for them to do.
        When deciding which processes to kill, the Android system weighs their relative importance to the user.
        For example, it more readily shuts down a process hosting activities that are no longer visible on screen,
        compared to a process hosting visible activities.
        The decision whether to terminate a process, therefore, depends on the state of the components running in that process.\n\n"

        "Threads\n\n"
        "When an application is launched, the system creates a thread of execution for the application, called main.
        This thread is very important because it is in charge of dispatching events to the appropriate user interface widgets,
        including drawing events. It is also almost always the thread in which your application interacts with components from
        the Android UI toolkit (components from the android.widget and android.view packages). As such, the main thread is also
        sometimes called the UI thread. However, under special circumstances, an app's main thread might not be its UI thread!!!
        \n\n"

       "The system does not create a separate thread for each instance of a component. All components that run in the same process are
        instantiated in the UI thread, and system calls to each component are dispatched from that thread. Consequently,
        methods that respond to system callbacks (such as onKeyDown() to report user actions or a lifecycle callback method)
        always run in the UI thread of the process.For instance, when the user touches a button on the screen,
        your app's UI thread dispatches the touch event to the widget,
        which in turn sets its pressed state and posts an invalidate request to the event queue. The UI thread dequeues the request
        and notifies the widget that it should redraw itself.\n\n"
        "When your app performs intensive work in response to user interaction, this single thread model can yield poor performance
        unless you implement your application properly. Specifically, if everything is happening in the UI thread, performing long
        operations such as network access or database queries will block the whole UI. When the thread is blocked, no events can be dispatched,
        including drawing events. From the user's perspective, the application appears to hang. Even worse, if the UI thread is blocked for more
        than a few seconds (about 5 seconds currently) the user is presented with the infamous application not
        responding (ANR) dialog. The user might then decide to quit your application and uninstall it if they are unhappy.\n\n"

        "Additionally, the Android UI toolkit is not thread-safe. So, you must not manipulate your UI from a worker thread—
        you must do all manipulation to your user interface from the UI thread.
        Thus, there are simply two rules to Android's single thread model:
        Do not block the UI thread
        Do not access the Android UI toolkit from outside the UI thread\n\n"
"Worker threads\n\n"
        "Because of the single threaded model described above, it's vital to the responsiveness of your application's UI that
        you do not block the UI thread. If you have operations to perform that are not instantaneous,
        you should make sure to do them in separate threads (background or worker threads).
        However, note that you cannot update the UI from any thread other than the UI thread or the main thread.
        To fix this problem, Android offers several ways to access the UI thread from other threads.\n\n"


    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
</resources>
